

Jermaine Varnicker

Data Scientist

- +27(0)78 032 3334
- Johannesburg/ South Africa
- www.linkedin.com/in/jermainevarnicker-315a8794/
- % https://github.com/JermaineV

ABOUT ME

I am a Fraud Analyst with over 10 years' experience working in the banking industry as well as freelance experience in the IT field. I am a recent IT systems development graduate and Microsoft certified T-SQL programmer. I have a keen interest in machine learning, and I am skilled in python programming, Data Wrangling, Statistical Data Analysis, Big Data Analytics, Data Science, and Data Visualization, Data modelling, Data Manipulation, ETL. All my academic results and projects can be found on the link provided: https://jermainev.github.io/

SKILLS



EDUCATION

IT System Development NQF 5

CTU Training Solutions
2020 – 2021

EXPERIENCE

Fraud and Disputes Specialist

FNB South Africa (2011- current)

- Fraud Document Compilation and Supply-Timely, accurate checking and comprehensive compilation and supply of fraud related documentation in the required format to support efforts in addressing identified fraud events.
- Service Delivery- Deliver exceptional service that exceeds customers' expectations through proactive, innovative, and appropriate solutions.
- Arbitration- Execute activities for arbitration of cases by preparing required information, which includes controlled sharing of customer information between banks, engaging with various stakeholders to validate any transactions.
- Case Recording and Monitoring- Recording and/or monitoring of fraud cases in internal and external databases.
- Fraud Information- Timely and accurate recording and checking of fraud related information to disseminate to relevant stakeholders.
- Fraud Process, Rules and System Compliance- Execute fraud administration duties in line
 with required rules, processes and using available systems. Ensure that activities are
 executed in a timely manner and accuracy.
- Operational Losses- Contribute to the reduction in operational losses by providing efficient administrative support to the fraud team.
- Recoveries- Execute recovery activities in line with applicable standards and laws to maximize recoveries for the Bank.
- Reporting Fraud Support- Compile and communicate accurate and timely reports on fraud according to area of focus

Reference: Emely Bogopane (Direct Manager)

National Diploma: Mechatronic engineering (incomplete)

University of South Africa 2014-(incomplete)

High School Diploma

Silver Oaks Secondary School 2002 - 2006



Exam 761: Querying Data with Transact-SQL – Microsoft

MCID: 990707958



IT Field Technician(Freelance)

Tell: 087 736 8449

JNT Computers (PTY) Ltd- (Jun 2015 - Apr 2016)

- Performing backups and installing hardware
- Installing printers and administering user accounts
- Ensuring adherence to quality standards in the organization
- Troubleshooting and resolving technical errors
- Attending to ad-hoc tasks and requests
- Maintaining of technological trends and developments
- Appointed as a computer service and maintenance technician
- Performing software installations and upgrades
- Installing, configuring, and providing support on network connections
- Assisting with ad-hoc technical assignments as required

Reference: Jimmy Jordaan (Director) 061 425 6760

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the authenticity of the above-mentioned particulars.

Signature_____